Joan Kouloumba

• DETAILS

+33 6 59 25 65 14 joankouloumba@yahoo.fr

Place of birth

Bangui, Central Africa Republic

Nationality

Central African / French

Driving license permis B

• SKILLS

Quality Management

Communication Skills

Microsoft Office

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Database Management

Leadership Skills

Computer Programming

Adaptability

organisational skills

Google Suite

• HOBBIES

travel and sport (Basket-ball, swimming, running)

• LANGUAGES

Sango, (Central African Republic)

French

English

• LINKS

My website resume & portfolio

LinkedIn profile

internship report at SIDEM as

PROFILE

With 7 year of experience in machining industry as quality technician, 3 year of experience in the private security sector as security agent and 6 year of experience in entrepreneurial projects in France and Central African Republic, I go on developing my skills in software and web development fields. During all this various professional experiences, I learn a lot on how to lead a project (PDCA), how to manage a production process with quality insurance, how to build an effective security system and so on. I am always up to take a new challenge and give the best of me, especially in a situation where i can optimize my bi-cultural background.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Product quality technician at Ensinger, Beynost, France

March 2020 — January 2021

- Program the automated control of machined parts on three-dimensional measuring machine with CALYPSO software.
 Result: insure the compliance of machined parts with the definition drawing.
- Calibrate measuring instruments like caliper, micrometer, comparator, buffer, etc. Result : reliable measuring tool
- Write control report following quality policies and procedures related. Result: traceability of the control and certification.
- Assist the quality manager in the quality management system. Result : better oversight of quality management organization

Production quality technician at CMW, Corbas, France

October 2016 — March 2020

- Manage production non-conformities and customers complaints with quality tools like 5P, FMECA, 5M, PARETO, Brainstorming, 8D, root cause analysis, etc. Result: Improvement of the production performance and customers satisfaction.
- Audit a production process, identify process deviations and set a corrective and preventive action plan. Result: sustainable targetcentric process.
- Build quality folder for customers consist of measuring reports, material certificate, supplier qualifications, First Article Inspection. Result: traceability
- Supervise the controller teams by distributing the tasks according to the capacities of each controller and by prioritizing the tasks according to the criteria of deadlines, costs and quality. Result:
 SMART organization of work

Security agent at PROSEGUR, Lyon, France

July 2016 — January 2019

- Monitor places, property and people. Result : keeping safe property and people.
- Perform intrusion risk detection patrols in a secure site. Result : secure an area

quality technician web development project achieved

- Check the access rights of cars and people by checking license plates and identity cards. Result : keeping safety area
- Apply first aid gesture to rescue people if needed. Result : be prepared to handle accident situation.

Production quality technician (work-study program) at ALSTOM POWER HYDRO, Grenoble, France

September 2013 — July 2014

- Edit and improve the quality control procedures according to the ALSTOM standards. Result: updated procedures
- Participate in quality department meetings: analysis of quality indicators, search for a solution to non-compliance. Result: better collaboration between workers.

EDUCATION

Web developer - professional qualification, OpenClassrooms, Lyon, France

July 2021 — January 2022

Web developer professional qualification equivalent of two years university degree :

learning computer programming with langage : HTML, CSS, Javascript. Framework : Vue, React, Node, Bootstrap. Database management system : MySQL, MongoDB

Auditor QMS ISO 9001 v2015 - professional qualification, CSP, Paris, France

September 2018 — September 2018

Quality Management System auditor on the standardization ISO 9001 version 2015

Security agent - professional qualification, Campus Science-U, Lyon, France

April 2016 — May 2016

Security agent - professional qualification : learn how to use security equipment, learn to build security system and perform first aid gesture and assistance.

Three year college degree - Industrial production, University Joseph Fourier, Grenoble, FRANCE

September 2011 — July 2014

3 year college degree in Industrial Production specialized in metrology, control and quality insurance

Y EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Entrepreneur in transportation sector, Lyon, FRANCE

March 2017 — February 2020

Self-employed in the transport and delivery of goods and setting up of my own company.

Entrepreneur in real estate, Bangui, CAR

January 2016

Manage a local real estate portfolio.

Drafting tenant lease agreements, supervising building renovation works, etc.

INTERNSHIPS

Quality technician at SIDEM, Suceava, ROMANIA, Europe

April 2011 — June 2011

 Deploy the Statistical Process Control (SPC) tool as control chart within production process. Result: improvement of the machining process

1 REFERENCES

Aurelia MAXUT from CMW

aura_maxut@yahoo.com · +33 6 95 23 80 23